kelvinwong.co.uk kelvinwong@outlook.com

DR KELVIN WONG

SUMMARY

Dr Kelvin Wong is a Senior Product Manager at Risk Management Solutions (RMS). He is a Chartered Geographer and Fellow of The Royal Geographical Society. At RMS, he works alongside a unique mix of climatologists, designers, seismologists, and mathematicians to design the best user experience for market-leading catastrophe modelling applications. Using science as a practical tool for solving real-life problems, his research to date applies to a wide range of domains, from autonomous vehicles to human behaviour understanding to transport planning.

EXPERIENCE

RISK MANAGEMENT SOLUTIONS

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER

Mar 2020 - Present

Models and Data Content Experience

UNIVERSITY OF TOKYO

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCH FELLOW—JAPAN SOCIETY FOR THE PROMOTION OF SCIENCE (JSPS)

Nov 2018 - Nov 2019

Kamijo Lab, Institute of Industrial Science

DEPARTMENT FOR TRANSPORT

GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEMS CONSULTANT

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Maritime Security and Resilience Division

EUROSDR

RESEARCHER

May 2018 – Oct 2018

Investigating the state of play of GeoBIM across Europe

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON

RESEARCHER-OPEN3D

May 2018 - Oct 2018

Department of Computer Science

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON

MODULE COORDINATOR—UNDERGRADUATE GIS (MATERNITY COVER)

Sep 2017 - Apr 2018

Department of Civil, Environmental and Geomatic Engineering

EUROSDR

RESEARCHER

Oct 2014 – Dec 2015

Economic Value of 3D Geographic Information

WSP GROUP

GIS ANALYST

Jan 2013 - Sep 2013

Planning and Development Department

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON

ENGD 3D GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SCIENCE

Apr 2018

Thesis: Towards a National 3D Mapping Product for Great Britain.

EngD Industry sponsor: Ordnance Survey (National Mapping Agency of Great Britain).

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON

MRES VIRTUAL ENVIRONMENTS, IMAGING & VISUALISATION

Sep 2014

Distinction. Thesis: Designing 3D Geographic Information for Navigation Using Google Glass.

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON

MSC GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SCIENCE

Sep 2012

Distinction. Thesis: Enhancing Positioning of Photovoltaic Panels Using 3D Geographic Information.

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHAMPTON

BSC GEOGRAPHY

Jul 2011

2:1. Thesis: Assessing Photovoltaic Potential in Hawaii.

YORK UNIVERSITY

SECOND YEAR EXCHANGE PROGRAM

Jan 2010 – Apr 2010

Department of Geography

ACCREDITATIONS AND MEMBERSHIPS

ROYAL GEOGRAPHICAL SOCIETY

CHARTERED GEOGRAPHER (GIS) & FELLOW OF THE ROYAL GEOGRAPHICAL SOCIETY

Sep 2020 - Present

DATA VIZUALISATION SOCIETY

MEMBER

Mar 2020 - Present

AWARDS, HONOURS, AND DISTINCTIONS

2019 Paper: Classifying Human Activity and Smartphone Holding Mode Using Accelerometer and Gyroscope

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON UCL STUDENT CHOICE AWARDS – EXCEPTIONAL FEEDBACK (NOMINATED)

2018 This award honours member of staff who provides constructive, useful feedback on students' assessment and

learning, helping them to progress and succeed.

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON HART PRIZE

2012 Awarded for most distinguished performance in the course by the Head of Department of Civil, Environmental and

Geomatic Engineering.

RESEARCH FUNDING

JAPAN SOCIETY FOR THE PROMOTION POSTDOCTORAL FELLOWSHIP FOR RESEARCH IN JAPAN (SHORT-TERM)

OF SCIENCE

The program provides PhD students or PhD researchers in the Europe and North America with opportunities to

conduct collaborative research under the guidance of their hosts in universities and other Japanese institutions.

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON UCL CENTRE VEIV ADVANCE SCHOLARSHIP

The UCL Center VEIV Advance Scholarships are small grants worth £4,500. The award is to support three months'

work in writing and submitting a research proposal or business plan relating directly to VEIV themes.

THE ENGINEERING AND PHYSICAL ENGINEERING DOCTORATE STUDENTSHIP AWARD – DEVELOPING A NEW 3D DATASET WITH THE ORDNANCE SCIENCES RESEARCH COUNCIL SURVEY

2013 The award provides a tax-free stipend of £18,590 per annum for four years, plus support for travel and research.

VOLUNTEERING

THE BRILLIANT CLUB PHD TEACHER

Sep 2015 – Feb 2016 The Scholars Programme recruits, trains, and places doctoral and postdoctoral researchers in schools to deliver

courses of university-style tutorials based on their own research.

AGE CONCERN IT SUPPORT

Jan 2015 – Jan 2017 Providing one-to-one personalised IT support at the client's own home for older residents who live in the borough of

Epsom and Ewell.

PUBLICATIONS

A full list of Kelvin's publications can be found at https://kelvinwong.co.uk/#publications

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PROGRAMMING, SCRIPTING & MARKUP Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Python, PHP, R, Markdown

FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES & Mapbox.js, leaflet.js, CesiumJS, GeoServer, d3.js, plotly.js, scikit-learn, Android SDK

TECHNOLOGIES

GEOSPATIAL ESRI GIS Products, QGIS, FME Desktop, Oracle Database, PostgreSQL, MySQL

AUTHORING AND DESIGN Microsoft Office—Word, Excel, PowerPoint, OneDrive, Outlook, OneNote

 ${\sf Google\:G\:Suite-Docs,\:Drive,\:Sheets,\:Forms,\:Sites,\:Apps\:Script}$

Adobe—Photoshop, Illustrator, Acrobat, InDesign

OTHER RELATED SOFTWARE Atlassian—Jira, Confluence, Jira Query Language (JQL), Jira Cloud platform REST API

LANGUAGES English (Native), Cantonese (Conversational), Japanese (Beginner)